# **Joseph Liang**

# Software Engineer

Oakland, CA 🔀 josephliang@outlook.com 🔗 jgoteam.github.io 🔘 jgoteam

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a full-stack Software Engineer with several years of experience in multiple languages and technologies, including JavaScript, Ruby, React, and Go. Stubbornly curious, I am passionate about clear, systematic thinking and the power of persistent, intentioned effort.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Co-Creator, Software Engineer,** Syncosaurus

2024 - present

Syncosaurus is an open-source, serverless framework for real-time, collaborative applications that features a synchronization system using client-side prediction and server reconciliation

- Designed, prototyped and contributed to key features of Syncosaurus's synchronization engine, including delta updates, message batching, automatic persistence, and connection state recovery
- Developed a token-based authentication interface to secure HTTP and Websocket traffic
- Automated provisioning of Cloudflare infrastrucuture with a CLI application (Node.js,TypeScript, oclif) to initialize, integrate, develop, manage, and deploy Syncosaurus projects
- Built an analytics dashboard (React, D3.js, Bootstrap, GraphQL), allowing developers to easily visualize and monitor hourly time-series usage and error metrics
- Wrote the documentation, which features an in-depth breakdown of core Syncosaurus concepts
- Co-authored a comprehensive case study on Syncosaurus's problem domain, use case, design decisions, and key engineering challenges, readable at https://syncosaurus.github.io/case-study ☑

## **Software Engineer.** Self-employed

2022 - present

Developed open-source web applications, including:

- Request Bucket: Tool for receiving, organizing, and debugging webhooks (Typescript, React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Nginx, DO droplet)
- MemDeck: Deck memorization toolkit app, with deck customization, record persistence, and a training mode (Ruby, Sinatra, ERB, PostgreSQL)

#### **Occupational Therapist**, Telecare, LCCA, Lifespan Therapy

2017 - 2022

- Designed, planned, and led the first occupational therapy program in a psychiatric health facility
- Conducted OT evaluations, developed appropriate care plans, and managed discharges for incoming referrals in the psychiatric, geriatric, and home health settings

# **SKILLS**

#### **Backend**

Node.js / Express, Go, Ruby / Sinatra, Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### Cloud

Cloudflare (Workers, Durable Objects, Pages, Queues), Digital Ocean Droplets, fly.io

#### Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, iQuery, Handlebars.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap, HTML / CSS

#### Other

Git / Github, Linux, Bash, Jest, Minitest, Nginx, Rest APIs, GraphQL, Websockets

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Saint Augustine**, *Master's of Occupational Therapy* 

2015 - 2017

University of California - San Diego, B.S. General Biology

2009 - 2013